# RYAN GLASS

(702) 426-8641 Ryanocanglass.phd@gmail.com

Ryan is an expert at applying his IT knowledge and skills to solve complex challenges. In his previous role, he was responsible for applying his technical know-how to manage and operate IT hardware, software and application solutions. On a personal level, he has the strong listening skills and the thirst for knowledge to continue learning. Right now, he would like to work for a company that offers its staff competitive pay, comprehensive benefits packages and outstanding future career advancement opportunities.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SEPTEMBER 2020 - CURRENT

#### FREELANCE ANDROID DEVELOPER, UPWORK

- Respond to client needs for applications with an eye to the most feasible and effective solutions.
- Coordinate with client to create apps in a coordinated and timely manner.
- Ensure that apps are tested to meet total performance requirements.
- Optimize the interfacing of the apps with a variety of systems to ensure flexible and agile use

#### JAN 2017 - JULY 2020

#### INFRASTRUCTURE ENGINEER, CLARK COUNTY SCHOOL DISTRICT

- Direct incident break/fix, application code deployment, configuration management, security management, engineering and implementation activities
- Define, drive and lead continuous improvement of service, technology and process improvement
- Partner with performance engineering and application development groups on project and production initiatives
- Resolve issues and escalate to DC network team management when necessary
- Create, review, and maintain documentation
- Advanced knowledge of interfacing technologies such as networking, database applications and data center technologies
- Define technical and procedural solutions for server monitoring, tuning and Capacity Management

#### **JUNE 2016 - DECEMBER 2016**

#### JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, UNITX

- Rendered solid technical expertise in SDLC and core Java technologies to develop applications based on specific client needs.
- Developed highly interactive and customized UIs using JavaScript, HTML, JSP, and CSS to improve functionality of web applications.
- Performed unit testing of applications by developing and applying test cases in Junit.

# **EDUCATION**

**MAY 2016** 

# BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF NEVADA LAS VEGAS

GPA: 3.6

COURSEWORK: Data structures, Systems programming, OS, Algorithms

## **SKILLS**

- Programming knowledge: SQL, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, Kotlin, Java
- Database knowledge: Oracle, MySQL, MSSQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Server virtualization
- Cloud computing

- IDE: Android Studio, Eclipse, IntelliJ, NetBeans
- Version Controls: SVN, Git
- Frameworks: Espresso, Picasso, OAuth, OKHTTP, .NET, Cordova
- Scripting